Hanna Bieri

Forster Strasse 54 10999 Berlin hannabieri.com hanna.bieri@gmail.com +4917676862705

Digital Product Designer

I am 23 years old, originally from Switzerland and am a highly motivated, likeable and enthusiastic person. By the age of 16, I took the decision to do an apprenticeship as a print media designer. It was 4-years training in and around everything related to print design. During that time, I really fell in love with print products, typography, neat kerning and detail-love. Afterwards, I took the decision to go back to school as I was keen to deepen my knowledge, especially in a digital direction. Currently, I study Interaction Design at CODE University of Applied Sciences in Berlin and work part-time as a UI-/UX-Designer for Diskutier Mit Mir e.V.

EDUCATION

Interaction Design, Bachelor of Arts

CODE University of Applied Science Berlin

● September 2018 – current

The CODE University of Applied Science is a project-based university with a focus on tech. Every semester students work either on real-world projects or on student-projects, accompanied by seminars and workshops. It builds upon the flipped-classroom concept and is focused on peer-to-peer-learning.

What I've learned so far:

- · research methods such as exploratory interviews and observation, evaluating results, ideation phases and iterative testing
- · basing design decisions on research and insights instead of a gut-feeling and "looks good"
- · User Interface Design for web and mobile applications, as well as how to add personality and an own look & feel to a brand for example in the semester project "Rowa", in which we've worked on strategies and a product on how to bring urban farming closer to the people
- being in an international environment and working multicultural teams, as at CODE, there are students of 60+ nationalities
- project groups are formed out of 3–6 students in an interdisciplinary teams of design – engineering – product management; as a result, I could gain a cross-disciplinary understanding

Vocational baccalaureate (Berufsmaturität 2, full-time), focus on design and art

Berufsbildungszenter Olten, BBZ · Switzerland

6 08/2016 - 07/2017

What I learned:

- · approaching art projects with a clear intention, how to develop a message with meaning and transfer it to the viewer; learning to deliver a conceptual approach to projects
- · reflecting on historical and current aspects of design, art and culture to be able to judge the quality of creative work
- · further development of basic design skills and abilities; improvement of three-dimensional imagination and a pronounced sense for proportions, colours, drawing, materials and font design
- · learning how to continuously acquire new skills and knowledge, especially with regard to the time after training
- · first experiences with digital design in a project about housing shortage

DESIGN **METHODS**

User Interviews

Sketching

Wireframing

Prototyping

User Interface Design

Visual Design

Usability Testing

SOFTWARE & TOOLS

Sketch

Adobe Xd

Figma

Photoshop

Illustrator

InDesign

After Effects

Premiere Pro

FRONT **END**

HTML CSS

Java Script –

in progress :-)

EXPERIENCE

UI-/UX-Designer, Working Student

Diskutier Mit Mir e.V. Berlin

October 2018 – current

Talking Europe is a pan-European platform for political dialogue. The application works with an algorithm, which connects citizens from different European countries with differing points of view and brings them together in an anonymous 1:1 conversation.

- responsible for the user experience as well as user interface design for the platform from User Flow Charts to final interfaces
- · working on a project with intercultural challenges, specificially about overcoming language and geographical barriers in political dialogue
- over a period of 1.5 months (April–May 2019, pre elections), reached 4.500 visitors on talkingeurope.com and over 40'000 chats. Countries of residence: Germany (28%), Spain (14%), UK (12%), Italy (14%), Poland (9%).
- part of the development of the Europe-wide social media campaign as well as creation of assets for various channels: reached 225.791 people on Facebook [7. May 2019], 271.000 impressions on Tweet [May 2019], 39.683 visits on Talking Europe [May 2019]

Training as a Media Designer Print

Rothus Grafik und Verlag, Solothurn · Switzerland

6 08/2012 - 08/2016

In the four year training as a media designer print, school and practical experience are brought together. While the theoretical basics are learnt and deepened in school, insights and experiences in the professional world are gained in practice.

- · design, creating and editing text and images for all types of print and screen media in a graphics studio of a publishing house for printed matter and digital media
- · a high degree of precision and high quality standards for everything that is implemented creatively: from posters, brochures and advertisements to campaigns, banners and signage
- \cdot an eye for detail, patience and persistence to strive for the highest quality
- direct customer contact, work according to customer order and independent organisation and coordination; systematic work and delivery on time
- · softwares (Adobe Creative Suite [Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, Bridge & Lightroom])
- · experience in a professional environment for 4 years

SPOKEN LANGUAGES

German · fluent

English · fluent

Spanish · basic

French · basic

MISCELLANEOUS & ACHIEVEMENTS

2017–2018 Stay abroad in Central & South America

2017 Award for "Best vocational baccalaureate" Berufsbildungszentrum Olten

2016–2017 Part-time employment in gastronomy, bartender at Red John Gastro GmbH